（サタン）愛はない
Love does not exist.
There is no such thing.
愛などない
故に悲しみもない
Therefore, there is no sadness.
そう思っていた
That is what I thought.
（デーモンたちの鳴き声）
（不動(ふどう) 明(あきら)）大丈夫？
Are you okay?
（飛鳥(あすか) 了(りょう)）もうダメだ 死ぬ
It's going to die.
（明）いや ダメ
No! Don't!
（了）もう死ぬんだ 寄こせ
It's gonna die. Give it to me.
（明）ダメ！
No!
（了）殺してやる
Let me kill it.
（明）ダメ ダメ！
No, you can't!
Why the hell not!?
クソッ 何でだ！
（サタン）私は嫌われ者で
お前は泣き虫で
People despised me.
And you were a crybaby.
（明）ええ… えーん えーん
AKIRA
ああ… あっく… えーん
（了）どうして泣く？
死ぬのは分かってた
Why are you crying?
You knew it was gonna die.
No.
（明）違う
（了）弱い者は死ぬ
The weak ones die.
（明）違う 違う 違う！
了ちゃんも泣いてる
No. That's not true.
You're crying, too, Ryo.
何で？ 俺は悲しくない
当然のことだ
Why? I'm not sad. It was gonna die.
You're crying, too, Ryo.
（明）了ちゃんも泣いてる
（サタン）その時 私は―
At the time...
お前が何を言ってるのか
分からなかったよ
I didn't know what you meant.
10 YEARS LATER
（了）明！ 今 お前が必要なんだ
Akira, I need you right now.
I Need You
（陸上部マネージャー）
位置について―
On your mark.
Get set.
よーい
（ピストルの音）
-Miko's boobs are bouncing like crazy.
-You pervert.
（陸上部員１）
ミーコの乳揺れ すっげ
（陸上部員２）どこ見てんだよ
速っ！ さすが上岡(かみおか)学院の魔女
So fast! Just what you'd expect
of Kamioka Academy's witch.
（陸上部員１）ドーピングでも
やってんじゃねえの？
She might be doping.
うちの女子と走りたくねえ
I don't wanna run with our school's girls.
（陸上部員２）あいつは
何で陸上やってっか不明
Why's that guy doing track-and-field?
（陸上部員１）美樹(みき)んとこの居候で
一緒に帰りたいだけなんじゃね？
He's staying at Miki's place.
（陸上部員１）美樹(みき)んとこの居候で
一緒に帰りたいだけなんじゃね？
（携帯電話の音）
-Maybe he wants to go home with her.
-Hide your phone.
お前 携帯
（陸上部員１）大丈夫っすよ
うちの顧問 ボケちゃってますから
It's fine.
Coach is senile.
Forget about my phone.
それよりスーパー高校生のアレ
It's that super high-schooler.
-Miki, you're amazing. You're so fast.
-You were fast, too, Miko.
（ミーコ）
すごい美樹 やっぱ速い
（牧村(まきむら)美樹）ミーコも速かった
MOYURU KODA
JYUNICHI KOTOBA
（陸上部員１）猟奇殺人っすからね
朝から やばいっす
What a bizarre murder.
It's all over the news.
TEAMMATE MURDERED
（記者１）
人１人死んでるんですよ
本当に何も知らないんですか
A person is dead.
Do you know nothing?
MOYURU KODA
（記者２）
中学のころからの―
You've been teammates for years, right?
チームメイト
だったんですよね？
（記者１）
怪しげなパーティーに―
There's a rumor you two went
to a questionable party.
一緒に行ったという
ウワサもありますが？
ドラッグパーティー？
A drug party?
“サバト”っていう悪魔崇拝
気取ったパーティーに―
Word is they went to some
pseudo-Satanic party called Sabbath.
行ってたらしいっすよ
速く走れるんなら
俺も悪魔と契約するけどな
I'd sign a deal with the Devil
if it'd make me run faster.
死んだヤツも速かったんだっけ？
Wasn't the guy who died fast, too?
（明）う… う…
（陸上部員２）えっ 何で？
What...? Why?
（陸上部員１）しかも涙
He's crying.
その人 泣いてる
That person is crying.
Akira's crying again.
Was someone sad?
（美樹）また明くん 泣いてる
悲しんでる人いた？
（明）う… うう…
スーパー高校生か
俺も友達死んだら泣くけどね
Ah, the super high-schooler.
I'd cry, too, if my friend died.
But this guy isn't crying, is he?
（陸上部員１）
でも こいつ泣いてないだろ
Why are you crying?
何でお前が泣くんだよ
ねえ ４継やろうよ
男女混合でさ
Oh, hey. Let's do a 4-by-100-meter relay.
A mixed relay.
イベントあるっていうじゃん？
-There's supposed to be an event, right?
-Seriously?
（陸上部員２）え～？
（陸上部員１）
スーコーがらみのイベントだろ？
Isn't it a memorial service?
Wonder what happens because of this case.
この事件でどうなるか
（美樹）ふふん
とか何とか言っちゃって
You seem concerned, but what you
really want is to run 4-by-100, right?
ホントは４継やりたいんでしょ？
（携帯電話の着信音）
（美樹）あっ
（ミーコ）長崎(ながさき)さんだ
It's Mr. Nagasaki.
あ ちょっとごめん
Sorry, gotta go.
（長崎光司(こうじ)）忙しい？
ちょうど今 近くで取材終わってさ
Are you busy?
I just finished an interview and
was wondering if you're hungry.
メシでもどうかと思ったんだけど
There's an Italian place
that's hard to get into.
（長崎）
なかなか予約取れないイタリアン
偶然 テーブルが１つ取れて
I got lucky and got a table.
THE TRACK WITCH
（陸上部員２）
美樹の写真撮ってる人？
-The guy taking photos of Miki?
-Probably her boyfriend.
（ミーコ）彼氏よ きっと
ええー？
はあ 全国のファンがっかり
-Fans across the county are bummed.
-She's out of your league, guys.
釣り合わないよ あんたらじゃ
だってスターだもん 美樹は
Miki is a star, after all.
（幸田(こうだ)のコーチ）
泣きべそかくな
Don't look like you're gonna cry.
How could you refuse to speak?
記者にだんまりとは
きちっと傷心のコメントでも
言えれば収まったのに
Things would've calmed down
if you looked upset.
The Asian Games are coming up.
すぐにアジア大会だ
You're suspected of doping,
so, prove your record
記録もドーピングが疑われてるから
今度の大会で証明しろ
in the game coming up.
For an idiot like you...
ぼんくらのお前には…
うお… うう…
（ミーコ）あっ いた！
There you are.
Akira,
have my parents buy you a phone.
明くん 携帯買ってもらいなよ
うちの親に気兼ねしてちゃダメだよ
You shouldn't feel hesitant with them.
I wouldn't really use it.
そんな使わないし
You can text all your
class and teammates.
クラスや部活のライン
やったほうがいいし―
And clear the history after you watch porn
居間のパソコンでエロいの見たら
履歴消しといて
-on the living room computer.
-The living room?!
（明）あっ！
（ミーコ）えー？
居間でそんなの見てんの？
I gotta do something.
I'll take the back way.
私 用事あるから 裏から帰るね
Even in a car, It's dangerous downtown,
（ミーコ）車だろうけど
下町 物騒だから気をつけて
-so, be careful.
-I won't be home late.
（美樹）遅くならずに帰りまーす
（ミーコ）じゃあねー
Bye.
不動くん 私たちも…
Fudo, we should...
（長崎）
ええ ハイソな若い連中の間で
はやってるんですよ
It's popular among the young people
in high society.
体力つくとか意思が強くなるとか
They say it fills you with
energy and willpower.
実際 豹変(ひょうへん)したり失踪したりって
話があって…
There are stories that people change,
or go missing...
MIKI:
I'M SORRY.
ああ ちょっとすいません
失礼しまーす
Oh, I have to go. Goodbye.
MIKI: IMPROMPTU PLANS FOR TRACK.
HAVE FUN.
（ハンドルをたたく音）
んんっ！
ああ 何やってんだろ 私
What am I doing?
（ビートボックスの音）
（美樹）あ…
This is the riverside
Where lowlifes gather
（ワム）
♪Yeah イキるリバーサイド
カスの吹き溜まり
The ones stuck here
All have foul mouths
はまっちまったヤツほど
口が悪(わ)りー
Success is hidden
behind the clouds here
ここじゃ成功ってやつも雲隠れ
俺たちの未来と空の色はグレイ
Our future and the sky are both gray
The air's dirty
The water's just as bad
常に空気がわりーし水もダメ
喘息(ぜんそく)が蔓延して身がもたねー
My asthma's worse
'm feeling weak
A place even God wants to leave
神様も逃げ出す
最底辺なら書き残す
An experience I can see
Only with my eyes
この眼しか見れない経験
Can't live luxuriously
カツカツな生活 できない贅沢(ぜいたく)
It's choking me
But it's my home
全てが窮屈
でも唯一のホームグラウンド
（美樹）あの…
通してください
Let me through.
（美樹）あの…
通してください
上げるのは根じゃなく名前だけ
I won't give up, but I'll shout my name
I made up my mind
上げるのは根じゃなく名前だけ
この決意に甘えはねー
で ツアーの感想はどう？
-So, what did you think of the tour?
-Hey, I've seen you before.
（ククン）あっ 見たことある
君 グラビア出てるよね
You do bikini modeling, don't you?
She's famous.
彼女有名だよ！ 高校陸上の魔女
-The witch of high school track-and-field.
-So, you can run fast?
へえ 走んの速いの？
Excuse me.
（明）あの！
（美樹）ん？
その… やめてください
Sir.
Please, stop.
（美樹）明くん！
Akira.
たまたま通りかか…
-I happened to pass by...
-Did you follow me?
（美樹）つけてきた？
（明）あはっ
（ワム）あのさ 今 海から―
Did you just come out
from the sea or something, Mr. Mermaid?
上がってきたわけじゃないよね
人魚さん？
Yup, I'm a mermaid just arrived
from the faraway sea.
（明）
今 遠い海から届いた人魚でーす
-Shut up.
-Then go back to the faraway sea.
（ククン）うっせえ
（ワム）じゃあ 遠い海に帰れ
（明）うわー！
（美樹）明くん！
Akira!
（車の音）
（美樹）え？
明！
Akira.
（ククン）今度は誰だよ
Who is it this time?
A guy in all-white,
and a coat in the summer?
（ワム）
真夏にコートの真白さんってか
（明）んん 了… ちゃん？
Ryo?
（美樹）え？
一緒に来てくれ 明！
Come with me, Akira.
（明）えっ？
（ククン）
あの 取り込み中なんですよ こっち
Excuse me.
We're in the middle of something.
お前ら 黙ってろ
You guys stay quiet.
（ワム）何だよ それ
-What did you just say?
-Akira.
（了）明！
（明）了ちゃん！ アハハ
Ryo.
（ワム）てめえ ざけやがって
Stop messing around!
（銃声）
（３人）わっ！ ちょちょっ…
Wow, wait, wait!
Why, you...
（ワム）こいつ…
Akira, come with me right away.
明 すぐ一緒に来てくれ
（美樹）明くん 誰 その人？
Akira, who is that guy?
飛鳥 了
Ryo Asuka. We're the same age,
but he's a professor in the States.
僕と同い年なのに
アメリカの大学で教授やってるんだ
Let's go.
（了）行くぞ！
No, don't go, Akira!
ダメ 明くん！
そんな人についていっちゃ
Don't follow a guy like that!
They're gone! Look at what you've done!
もう！ 行っちゃったじゃない
何やってんのよ
（ククン）速…
She's so fast.
Ryo, is that...?
了ちゃん それ…
マシンガンだ
A machine gun.
そうじゃなくて
Not that.
法律を守っていては生きていけない
You can't survive by obeying laws.
アメリカの免許では
日本で車の運転もできない
You can't drive in Japan
with an American license.
じゃ 無免許？
-You're driving without a license?
-Get a phone.
（了）携帯を持て
分からないから
女のＧＰＳをたどった
I couldn't track your GPS,
so I tracked the girl's.
（明）美樹ちゃん知ってんの？
-You know Miki? How'd you find--?
-Why do you run?
どうやって美樹ちゃんの…
（了）なぜ走る？
（明）陸上あるあるだよね
よく聞かれるけど
It's common in track.
People ask a lot.
（了）
人間が移動しようとしても―
The human ability of movement
犬 猫 小鳥にさえ
身体能力は及ばない
can never reach
those of dogs, cats, or birds.
（了）人間の能力は
武器や乗り物を使えてこそだ
Weapons and vehicles are what bring out
the abilities of humans.
（明）うん
先月 フィキラが死んだ
ロシアの学者だ
Fikira died last month.
He was a Russian scholar.
I was asked
to research the ancient people,
（了）俺は古代先住民を
研究しているという彼に頼まれて―
現地アマゾンに古く伝わる
言語の通訳をするため―
and in order to learn an old language
of the Amazon,
I went deep into the jungle.
ジャングルの奥地へ分け入った
（ノック）
（英語：了）フィキラ教授？
Professor Fikira?
（ドアが開く音）
（英語：了）フィキラ教授？
（机にたたきつける音）
（英語）フィキラ…
Professor.
（机にたたきつける音）
（英語：フィキラ）
鳥がうるさくてねえ
The chirping birds were getting
on my nerves.
だけど ようやく静かになった
But they're caught now, finally.
静かになった…
They're quiet now.
（スズムシの鳴き声）
That can't be.
まさか…
（物音）
うっ！
（フィキラ）うわあー！ あっ
（銃声）
はあ はあ…
（英語）ああ これは…
This is...
ウガァァァァ
ウガ！
Hey, what are you doing?
（英語：了）おい 何を！
I can't keep it down.
（英語）無理だ 抑えきれない
I must die while I'm still human.
人間のうちに死ぬしかない
Damn it.
（ロシア語）クソッ
（英語：了）よせ！ 爆発するぞ！
No, you'll explode.
A shame, since I came
to know more about you.
（ロシア語）俺は お前を
調べに来たはずなのに
ブォアアアアアア
You devil. Damn it.
（ロシア語：フィキラ）
悪魔め～ くそお
（悪魔）ギャアーオアア
（爆発音）
Fikira's burnt corpse weighed
twice as much as he did when he was alive.
黒コゲになったフィキラの重さは
生きている時の倍あった
（明）ん？
炭化したのに
２倍の重さがあった…
Twice as heavy,
even though he was charred.
Something was inside him.
何かがフィキラの中にいた
ん？ 何かって
Something?
A devil.
悪魔だ
（明）ハハッ 悪魔？
A devil?
The natives he was researching
were the devils.
彼が調べていた先住民とは
悪魔のことだったんだ
悪魔は人間が地球に現れる
はるか昔から存在した
Devils have existed
on Earth since long before humans.
どう猛で野蛮きわまりなく
感情などない
They are ferocious, extremely savage,
and have no emotion.
しかし戦闘能力と
生命力に長(た)けた生物
But they are creatures skilled at fighting
and surviving.
No devil has ever
been seen in it's true form.
単体での目撃例はなく
悪魔は実体を持たず―
They cannot exist unless they
merge with some living thing.
何かしら生物と合体しないと
存在できない
They merged
with superior creatures each time
ヤツらは生きのびるために
より良い生物と合体を繰り返し―
in order to survive,
その能力を蓄え 進化していった
keeping their abilities and evolving.
（明）増えた体重の分は
悪魔だってこと？
You mean the extra weight was a devil?
（了）そして今 巧妙に―
And now there are devils
who have gained the ability
人間の体を保ったまま
生活する術(すべ)を手に入れた悪魔もいる
to live while still keeping a human body.
逆に人間からすれば
悪魔の意思に負けなければ―
On the other hand,
if we don't lose to the devil's will,
人間でありながら 悪魔の力を
手に入れることも可能なわけだ
it's possible to gain its power
while remaining a human.
多分 フィキラは
それを身を持って示そうとし―
Fikira probably tried
to prove that with his own body.
失敗した
But he failed.
There have been a lot of cases lately
近年 世界で頻発している
残忍な謎の未解決事件
of brutal unsolved mysteries.
謎の大量失踪
急に粗暴になった人々の報告
Strange mass disappearances,
reports of unprecedented violence,
突然 驚異的な身体能力を発揮した
スポーツ選手や―
athletes who suddenly show
astounding physical abilities,
and other things seen by people.
一般人の目撃例
Those phenomena dovetail perfectly
and can be explained easily.
それらの現象は
ピタリと符合して説明がつく
悪魔が広がっているんだ
The devils are spreading.
The heads of police
and the Public Security Division
世界各地の警察上層部や公安は
この事実をつかんでいるに違いない
around the world must know.
何で公表しないの？
-Why haven't they made it public?
-They're scared of a panic.
パニックを怖れているんだ
しかし それが真実なら
皆が知るべきだ
But if it's the truth,
everyone should know.
It'll be a disaster if people don't
take precautionary measures on their own.
知って各自 警戒対策を
とらなければ大変なことになる
フィキラの仮説が事実なら
確かめて証拠を集め世界に訴える
If Fikira's hypothesis is true,
we're going to confirm it, get evidence,
and tell the world. That's my mission.
これは使命だ
Is it here?
ここ？
巻き込んでしまってすまない
Sorry for dragging you into this.
できれば お前と一緒に
真相を突き止めたいと思った
If possible,
I wanted to find out the truth with you.
しかし それには
大きな危険がともなう
But there's a big risk that comes with it.
You might get eaten by a devil,
悪魔に食われたり
フィキラと同じように―
or end up pouring gasoline over your head,
just like Fikira.
頭からガソリンをかぶるハメになる
可能性もある
了ちゃん 何で僕を？
Ryo, why me?
俺は怖いんだ
怖くて怖くてたまらない…
I'm scared.
I'm so terrified.
これはフィキラが
俺に残した恐怖の遺産だ
This is a horrific legacy
that Fikira left me.
真実を突き止めなければならない
I must find out the truth.
しかも なるだけ早く―
And I wanted to tell this to you
before anyone else,
俺は誰よりも
まず お前に知らせたかった
as soon as I could.
俺が信用できるのは
お前しかいないんだ
You're the only one I can trust.
手伝ってほしい！
皆に事実を知らせる
I need your help.
We're gonna tell everyone the truth.
生きて帰ったら 皆は俺たちに
感謝することになる！
When we go back alive,
everyone will thank us.
ありがとう
分かったよ 了ちゃん
Thanks.
Okay, Ryo.
僕は了ちゃんを信じるよ！
I trust you, Ryo.
ありがとう明 行くぞ！
（明）うん
Thanks, Akira.
Let's go.
（了）もう後戻りはできない
悪魔の証拠をつかむんだ
There's no going back.
We're going to prove devils exist!
（了）もう後戻りはできない
悪魔の証拠をつかむんだ
（電子音）
（了）もう後戻りはできない
悪魔の証拠をつかむんだ
（クラブの音楽）
Here you go.
（受美(すみ)）はい どーぞ
（受美）
デビデビのほうがよかった？
Do you prefer Devidevi?
あっ…あ がっ…
（受美）はん… んん
（明）はっ んん…
んっ ああっ！
アッハハ！ 彼 初めて？
Is he a first-timer?
（了）
ああ 彼女にフラれたばかりで
Yeah,
he just got dumped by his girl.
かわいい！
（明）あっ！
He's cute.
会えたら あとでね！
Hope to bump into you later.
（明）あ… ああ…
（男）あーん
（了）最近 流行のパーティー
“サバト”だ
It's Sabbath, the latest popular party.
What? Are we going to summon the devil?
（明）え？ 悪魔を呼び出すの？
I know the Sabbath party is
where people get possessed by devils.
サバトパーティーが―
悪魔に憑依(ひょうい)される現場と
なっているのは つかんでいる
But the devil won't come
to a fake scene like this.
だが こんなフェイクじゃ
悪魔は来ない
了ちゃん… ん？
Ryo.
はあ…
（女１）きゃあ！
（明）はっ！
デーモンは血を好む！
Demons love blood.
りょっ…
Ryo.
What's wrong?
（男１）おい どうした
（男２）何だ？
What is it?
There's blood!
（男１）血だぞ
（男２）おい！
-Hey!
-That guy!
（男１）あいつ！
Ryo.
了ちゃん… あっ
Both Black Mass
and Sabbath come with blood.
黒ミサもサバトも
血とともにある！
Blood.
血だ 血だ 血だ
Blood! Blood!
（明の荒い息）
Stop! Ryo, stop it!
やめて！ 了ちゃん やめてよ
どうせクズばかりだ
悲しむことはない
They're all scum anyway.
There's no need to be sad.
（男３）てめえもクズだろ
You're scum, too!
あっ 了ちゃん！
-Ryo!
-You, too!
（男４）お前もだ！
（明）あああっ
ぐっ
（男５）いやっ んっ ふんっ！
（瓶が割れる音）
（男６）ふっ でえ！
You want to touch my boobs?
Look behind you.
あら オッパイ欲ちいの～？
後ろ見て！
おら～！
Take that!
（明）ぐああ…
（受美）アハハ
アハハハハハハハ…
うっげー！
ううう…
うおおおう！
うわあ… おう おおお！
（乳房デーモン）
うおおおう！ …うぇあ
（男７）ひいっ うああ！
うあああう
（男８）う… うわ… ああああーっ
（男９）ぐぅ！
（男10）んっ！
It started.
始まった！
（明）ああ…
No.
（女２）あああ！
助けてええええ！
Help me!
（男11）だって… ああっ！
But...
（男12）はああ ああああ！
（デーモンの叫び声）
（男13）はああっ
（女３）あああ うぐ
（悪魔語：了）
アモン！ チャンスだぞ―
Amon. Now's your chance.
Possess Akira. Amon.
明へとりつけ！ アモン！
（男14）うわ あああ
（男15）あああっ
（男16）はああっ！
は… は… は… は… は…
（了）あっ
うっく！
Ryo!
了ちゃん！
（明の荒い息）
（了）なぜ走る？
Why do you run?
犬猫にさえ
身体能力はかなわないのに
Your physical ability is nothing,
compared to even cats and dogs.
悪魔に食われる
食われる… 食われる… 食われる…
You would get eaten by a devil.
Eaten... Eaten...
（明）うあああ ああああ
ああああああ
（うなり声）
（明）うおおおお
ううっ！
（デビルマン）
バオオオオォォォーッ
Amon?
（デーモンたち）アモンガアモン？
（デーモン）ひいっ
（デビルマン）グワー
（デーモンを引き裂く音）
I've made Akira into a devil.
（了）俺は明をも
悪魔にしてしまった
（了）しかも無慈悲で残忍な
最強の悪魔を―
And...
I might have created the most powerful,
ruthless, and brutal devil in this world.
この世に作り出して
しまったのではないか？
&lrm;
Subtitles by
Daniel Marchildon